[
  {
    "question": "1. JavaScript is the programming language of the _____.",
    "choices": [
      "Desktop",
      "Mobile",
      "Web",
      "Server"
    ],
    "answer": "Web"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Which type of JavaScript language is _____?",
    "choices": [
      "Object-oriented",
      "Object-based",
      "Functional programming",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Object-based"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which of the following statement(s) is true about the JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "It is a scripting language used to make the website interactive",
      "It is an advanced version of Java for Desktop and Mobile application development",
      "It is a markup language of Java to develop the webpages",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "It is a scripting language used to make the website interactive"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. In which HTML element, we put the JavaScript code?",
    "choices": [
      "<javascript>...</javascript>",
      "<js>...</js>",
      "<script>...</script>",
      "<css>...</css>"
    ],
    "answer": "<script>...</script>"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. JavaScript code can be written in ____.",
    "choices": [
      "JavaScript file (.js file)",
      "HTML document directly",
      "JavaScript file and in HTML document directly",
      "In style sheets (.css file)"
    ],
    "answer": "JavaScript file and in HTML document directly"
  },
  {
    "question": "6. Which symbol is used separate JavaScript statements?",
    "choices": [
      "Comma (,)",
      "Colon (:)",
      "Hyphen (_)",
      "Semicolon (;)"
    ],
    "answer": "Semicolon (;)"
  },
  {
    "question": "7. JavaScript ignores?",
    "choices": [
      "newlines",
      "tabs",
      "spaces",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Which is the correct syntax to call an external JavaScript file in the current HTML document?",
    "choices": [
      "<script src=\"jsfile.js\"></script>",
      "<script href=\" jsfile.js\"></script>",
      "<import src=\" jsfile.js\"></import>",
      "<script link=\" jsfile.js\"></script>"
    ],
    "answer": "<script src=\"jsfile.js\"></script>"
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which JavaScript method is used to access an HTML element by id?",
    "choices": [
      "getElementById()",
      "getElement(id)",
      "getElementById(id)",
      "elementById(id)"
    ],
    "answer": "getElementById(id)"
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Which property is used to define the HTML content to an HTML element with a specific id?",
    "choices": [
      "innerText",
      "innerContent",
      "elementText",
      "innerHTML"
    ],
    "answer": "innerHTML"
  },
  {
    "question": "11. Which JavaScript method is used to write HTML output?",
    "choices": [
      "document.write()",
      "document.output()",
      "console.log()",
      "document.writeHTML()"
    ],
    "answer": "document.write()"
  },
  {
    "question": "12. Which JavaScript method is used to write on browser's console?",
    "choices": [
      "console.write()",
      "console.output()",
      "console.log()",
      "console.writeHTML()"
    ],
    "answer": "console.log()"
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Which JavaScript method is used to write into an alert box?",
    "choices": [
      "window.alertHTML()",
      "window.alert()",
      "window.alertBox()",
      "window.alertContent()"
    ],
    "answer": "window.alert()"
  },
  {
    "question": "14. Which is the correct JavaScript statement to display \"Hello Boss!\" into an alert box?",
    "choices": [
      "alert(\"Hello Boss!\");",
      "alert('Hello Boss!');",
      "alert(Text:'Hello Boss!');",
      "Both A. and B."
    ],
    "answer": "Both A. and B."
  },
  {
    "question": "15. Which is the correct JavaScript statement to print the addition of two numbers 10 and 20 in a paragraph whose id is 'result'?",
    "choices": [
      "getElementById(\"result\").innerHTML = 10+20;",
      "getElementById(\"result\").innerHTML = \"10+20\";",
      "getElementById(\"#result\").innerHTML = 10+20;",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "getElementById(\"result\").innerHTML = 10+20;"
  },
  {
    "question": "17. In JavaScript, single line comment begins with ___.",
    "choices": [
      "#",
      "/*",
      "$",
      "//"
    ],
    "answer": "//"
  },
  {
    "question": "18. In JavaScript, multi-line comments start with __ and end with ___.",
    "choices": [
      "/* and */",
      "<!â€”and -->",
      "## and ##",
      "// and //"
    ],
    "answer": "/* and */"
  },
  {
    "question": "19. Which JavaScript keyword is used to declare a variable?",
    "choices": [
      "Var",
      "var",
      "Let",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "var"
  },
  {
    "question": "20. How many keywords are there in JavaScript to declare variables or constants?",
    "choices": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "21. What is the main difference between var and let keywords in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "var defines a variable while let defines a constant",
      "var defined function scoped variable while let define block scoped variable",
      "The value of a variable declared with var can be changed while the value of a variable declared with let cannot be changed",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "var defined function scoped variable while let define block scoped variable"
  },
  {
    "question": "22. The const keyword is used to define a ______.",
    "choices": [
      "Function scopes variable",
      "Block scoped variable",
      "Constant",
      "Constant with no initial value"
    ],
    "answer": "Constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Which is the correct syntax to declare a constant in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "const constant_name;",
      "constant_name const;",
      "constant_name const = value;",
      "const constant_name = value;"
    ],
    "answer": "const constant_name = value;"
  },
  {
    "question": "25. What is the default value of an uninitialized variable?",
    "choices": [
      "0",
      "undefined",
      "null",
      "NaN"
    ],
    "answer": "undefined"
  },
  {
    "question": "27. Can be redeclare a variable that is declared with var keyword?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "question": "30. Can be redeclare a variable that is declared with let keyword?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "answer": "No"
  },
  {
    "question": "32. Which is the exponentiation operator in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "exp()",
      "^",
      "**",
      "pow"
    ],
    "answer": "**"
  },
  {
    "question": "33. Does JavaScript support increment (++) and decrements (--) Operators?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "question": "37. JavaScript types are _____.",
    "choices": [
      "Static",
      "Dynamic"
    ],
    "answer": "Dynamic"
  },
  {
    "question": "38. JavaScript arrays are written with _____.",
    "choices": [
      "round brackets ()",
      "curly brackets {}",
      "double quotes \"\"",
      "square brackets []"
    ],
    "answer": "square brackets []"
  },
  {
    "question": "39. JavaScript objects are written with _____.",
    "choices": [
      "round brackets ()",
      "curly brackets {}",
      "double quotes \"\"",
      "square brackets []"
    ],
    "answer": "curly brackets {}"
  },
  {
    "question": "40. Which JavaScript operator is used to determine the type of a variable?",
    "choices": [
      "typeof",
      "TypeOf",
      "typeOf",
      "sizeof"
    ],
    "answer": "typeof"
  },
  {
    "question": "41. Which is the correct syntax of JavaScript typeof operator?",
    "choices": [
      "typeof variable/value",
      "typeof(variable/value)",
      "Both A. and B.",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Both A. and B."
  },
  {
    "question": "43. Which keyword is used to define a JavaScript function?",
    "choices": [
      "module",
      "fun",
      "func",
      "function"
    ],
    "answer": "function"
  },
  {
    "question": "44. Which is the correct syntax for the function definition?",
    "choices": [
      "return_type function function_name(parameter1, parameter2, ...) { /*Function's body*/ }",
      "function function_name(parameter1, parameter2, ...) { /*Function's body*/ }",
      "return_type function_name(parameter1, parameter2, ...) { /*Function's body*/ }",
      "function function_name(parameter1, parameter2, ...) as return_type { /*Function's body*/ }"
    ],
    "answer": "function function_name(parameter1, parameter2, ...) { /*Function's body*/ }"
  },
  {
    "question": "46. Can we use a function as a variable value?",
    "choices": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ],
    "answer": "Yes"
  },
  {
    "question": "47. In JavaScript a variable contains one value while an object may contain ___.",
    "choices": [
      "One value",
      "Two values",
      "Three values",
      "Many values"
    ],
    "answer": "Many values"
  },
  {
    "question": "48. Which is the correct syntax to access an object property in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "objectName:propertyName",
      "propertyName",
      "objectName[\"propertyName\"]",
      "Both B. and C."
    ],
    "answer": "Both B. and C."
  },
  {
    "question": "49. Which property is used to get the length of a string in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "strlen",
      "len",
      "length",
      "Length"
    ],
    "answer": "length"
  },
  {
    "question": "51. Which character is used to break up a code line within a text string in JavaScript?",
    "choices": [
      "Single quote (')",
      "Single backslash (\\)",
      "Double quote (\")",
      "Tipple single quote (''')"
    ],
    "answer": "Single backslash (\\)"
  },
  {
    "question": "53. Which is the correct JavaScript statement to define string as object?",
    "choices": [
      "var s = new String(\"IncludeHelp!\");",
      "var s = String(\"IncludeHelp!\");",
      "var s = \"IncludeHelp!\"",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "var s = new String(\"IncludeHelp!\");"
  },
  {
    "question": "55. Which is/are the valid JavaScript method(s) to extract string parts?",
    "choices": [
      "slice(start, end)",
      "substring(start, end)",
      "substr(start, length)",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "57. In JavaScript, the string template literals use ____ rather than the quotes (\"\") to define a string?",
    "choices": [
      "Single quotes ('')",
      "Backslash with single quote (\\â€™'\\')",
      "Backslashes (\\\\)",
      "Back-ticks (``)"
    ],
    "answer": "Back-ticks (``)"
  },
  {
    "question": "59. Which JavaScript method is used to get a number as a string?",
    "choices": [
      "toString()",
      "intToString()",
      "parseInteger()",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "toString()"
  },
  {
    "question": "67. Which JavaScript method is used to call a function (a callback function) once for each array element?",
    "choices": [
      "for()",
      "traverse()",
      "forEach()",
      "foreach()"
    ],
    "answer": "forEach()"
  },
  {
    "question": "70. Which JavaScript method is used to create a new array with array elements that passes a test?",
    "choices": [
      "forEach()",
      "map()",
      "forMap()",
      "filter()"
    ],
    "answer": "filter()"
  },
  {
    "question": "71. Which JavaScript object works with the dates?",
    "choices": [
      "Date",
      "DateTime",
      "date",
      "dateTime"
    ],
    "answer": "Date"
  },
  {
    "question": "72. Which JavaScript statement(s) is correct to create Date object(s) with new Date() constructor?",
    "choices": [
      "new Date()",
      "new Date(year, month, day, hours, minutes, seconds, milliseconds)",
      "new Date(milliseconds)",
      "new Date(date string)",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "74. Which JavaScript method is used to convert a date to a UTC string (a date display standard)?",
    "choices": [
      "toUTCString()",
      "toUtcString()",
      "utcString()",
      "toutcstring()"
    ],
    "answer": "toUTCString()"
  },
  {
    "question": "75. The internal clock in JavaScript counts from midnight _____.",
    "choices": [
      "January 1, 1972",
      "January 1, 1947",
      "January 1, 1980",
      "January 1, 1970"
    ],
    "answer": "January 1, 1970"
  },
  {
    "question": "76. What does the Date object's method getTime() return?",
    "choices": [
      "Date in DD-MM-YYYY format",
      "Date in DD MON YYYY format",
      "Date in MON, DD YYYY format",
      "Number of milliseconds since January 1, 1970"
    ],
    "answer": "Number of milliseconds since January 1, 1970"
  },
  {
    "question": "77. Which method is used to get the year of a date as a four-digit number?",
    "choices": [
      "getYear()",
      "fullYear()",
      "getFullYear()",
      "getfullyear()"
    ],
    "answer": "getFullYear()"
  }
]